A new era of wonder begins.
Wonder Woman 1984 is a action, adventure, fantasy
film directed by Patty Jenkins.
A botched store robbery places Wonder Woman in a global battle against a powerful
and mysterious ancient force that puts her powers in jeopardy.
Diana Prince, played by Gal Gadot.
Steve Trevor, played by Chris Pine.
Barbara Minerva, played by Kristen Wiig.
Maxwell Lord, played by Pedro Pascal.
Antiope, played by Robin Wright.
Hippolyta, played by Connie Nielsen.
Wonder Woman 1984 (also stylized as WW84) is a 2020 American
superhero film based on the DC character Wonder Woman.
Produced by Warner Bros.
Pictures, Atlas Entertainment, and The Stone Quarry, and distributed by Warner Bros., it is a sequel
to the 2017 film Wonder Woman and the ninth film in the DC Extended Universe (DCEU).
The film was directed by Patty Jenkins from a screenplay she co-wrote with Geoff
Johns and Dave Callaham, based on a story by Jenkins and Johns.
It stars Gal Gadot as Diana Prince / Wonder Woman, alongside Chris Pine,
Kristen Wiig, Pedro Pascal, Robin Wright, and Connie Nielsen.
Set in 1984 during the Cold War, the film follows Diana and her past love
Steve Trevor as they face off against Maxwell Lord and Cheetah.
Discussion of a sequel began shortly after the release of the first film in June
2017 and the decision to proceed was confirmed the following month.
Principal photography began on June 13, 2018, with
filming taking place at Warner Bros.
Studios, Leavesden in England, as well as the District of Columbia and Northern Virginia in the U.S.,
London and Duxford in England, Tenerife and Fuerteventura in the Canary Islands and Almería.
Production wrapped on December 22, 2018, after a six-month
shoot, with additional filming in July 2019.
Following multiple delays due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Wonder Woman 1984 eventually premiered on December 15,
2020, via the DC FanDome virtual platform, and was released in the United States by Warner Bros.
Pictures on December 25, 2020.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $169 million
worldwide, failing to break even against its $200 million budget.
Its underperformance at the box office was attributed to factors such as most theaters being closed during the
pandemic and the film's simultaneous release on HBO Max, where it became the top streaming film of 2020.
Plans for a third film were canceled after DC Films was
restructured into DC Studios in 2022.
A spin-off prequel series focusing on the Amazons of
Themyscira, Paradise Lost, is in development.
The film explores themes of superhero, based on comic,
woman director, 1980s, action hero.